# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hey guys I am Wang Gang
# 今天的视频我要和大家分享
In today's video I'm gonna show you
# 茄子的八种切法
Eight ways of cutting eggplants
# 其实茄子的切法远远不止八种
In fact, there are more than 8 ways of cutting eggplants
# 本次跟大家分享普通家庭中能用得上的8种
The 8 techniques shown here are useful in ordinary home-cooking
# 首先我们用滚刀的方式去掉茄子蒂
First, remove the stem of the eggplant in "Gun Dao" (lit. "rolling cut") technique
# 茄子蒂也可以食用喜欢的同学可以保留
The stem is also edible. You can keep it if you like
# 当然了嫌麻烦的同学可以直接切来扔掉
Or just remove it if you'd like to avoid troubles
# 首先跟大家分享第一种切法
The first technique:
# 将茄子从中间切开然后切成均匀的小条
Cut the eggplant in between, and then cut evenly into long and narrow strips
# 最后再切成段即可、
At last cut short the long pieces
# 这一种形状的茄子比较适合红烧
Pieces of this shape are suitable for red-braise
# 切的时候尽量切小条均匀一些
Try to cut it as evenly as you can
# 这样才更容易炸透
in order to make it easier to fry thoroughly
# 下面是第二种
Next is the second technique
# 此法是将茄子放在菜板上面滚着切成块
we do it by cutting the eggplants into lumps while rolling the eggplant
# 所以此法俗称“滚刀块”
That's why this technique is called "Gun Dao Kuai" (lit. lumps cut by rolling the object
# 它原理就像削铅笔一样简单
It is so easy like sharpening your pencil
# 切熟练之后即可这样快速的滚起来切
After you become skillful at it you can do faster like me
# 这个切法适合做“茄子烧肉”“地三鲜”或者“红烧茄子”
This way fits cooking of red-braised eggplants or "Di San Xian" (Sauteed Potato, green pepper, and eggplant)
# 下面是第三种
The third technique:
# 首先将茄子从中间切开一分为四
First, cut the eggplants into four parts
# 然后将茄子翻面切刀切成菱形块
Flip the slices and further cut them into diamond-shaped pieces
# 菱形块的形状比滚刀块更美观
The diamond shape is prettier than Gun Dao Kuai
# 这个切法同样比较适合第二种适合做的菜
And also fitting the dishes made by the second technique
# 下面是第四种
Next is the forth one:
# 将茄子先切成后片再摆好之后切成丝
Cut the eggplants into round slices, and then into strips
# 切丝的茄子适合爆炒或者清炒
Eggplant strips are suitable for stir-frying
# 所以我们不能切太细否则容易炒烂
So the strips need to be a bit thicker so as not to melt in cooking
# 大家可以看一下基本上切成薯条大小即可
You can have a look. The size is roughly the same as chips/fries
# 下面是第五种
The fifth one
# 第五种切法是最常见之一
which is one of the most common techniques
# 种中间切开之后直接切成片即可
Slice the eggplant after cutting it into two
# 同样也是众多切法种最家常的一种
So this technique is most homely
# 适合清炒爆炒类的做法
Suitable for stir-frying
# 这里大家需要注意的是
One thing you need to pay attention to:
# 尽量切成大小一致的厚度
The size and thickness of the slices should be roughly the same
# 下面开始第六种
Now we start the sixth one
# 首先我们把茄子头横切下来
First we cut off the head of the eggplants (not using Gun Dao)
# 然后切第一刀不切断
the first cut avoids cutting off
# 在切第二刀的时候切断
The second cut makes the lump
# 此法切的茄子适合在中间加入肉泥炸茄盒
The shape is often for frying meat-stuffed eggplant
# 大家可以按照自己的喜好来控制厚度
You can decide the thickness as you like it
# 切的时候尽量保持四分之一的连接
When you do the first cut, try to keep its depth at about 3/4 diametre
# 这样才能放入更多的肉
so that you can put in meat stuff as much as possible
# 下面开始第七种切法
Then the seventh way:
# 首先把茄子从中间切开
Cut the eggplant in between into two parts
# 然后斜刀切进茄子的四分之三
Then slant-cut to 3/4 depth of the eggplant
# 每刀之间的间隔大概4毫米
The gap between cuts is about 4 mm
# 然后再反过来同样斜刀切另一面
turn the eggplant around and slant-cut again
# 这个切法的茄子适合做成鱼香茄子
This technique is suitable for "Yu Xiang Qie Zi" (lit. Eggplant cooked with fish aroma)
# 此法的优势是更容易炸透和入味
because it will be easier to cook, and the flavour can penetrate easily
# 剩下的一半以正常速度展示
The other part will be cut in my normal speed
# 最后一种切法是最盘龙茄子
The last technique is "Pan Long Qie Zi" (lit. Coiled dragon eggplant)
# 首先在茄子的正面切进去
Cut the eggplant on one side
# 每一刀之间的间隔大概3mm
Leave a ~3 mm gap between each cut
# 然后翻过来斜刀切另一面
Flip the eggplant and cut the other side
# 此法在之前的盘龙茄子种有更详细的切法和做法
This technique is fully illustrated in the previous video of Pan Long Qie Zi
# 好了本期视频到此结束
Okay. That's all for today's video
# 后续会跟大家带来更多切法小技巧
In later videos I will share with you more cutting tips